我在考虑留个山羊胡
I'm thinking about growing a goatee.
你那样是范·戴克式胡
Oh, actually that's a Van Dyke.
山羊胡的话就只留下巴处
A goatee is just hair on the chin.
等等  那如果是只有上面这块的胡须呢
Oh. Wait, then what is it if you just have hair up here?
你是指笑虎子吗
You mean a moustache?
-"笑虎子"  -他那么念啦
- Moo-stache! - He said it!
笑吧笑吧  随便取笑外国来的吧
Ha-ha, very funny. Make fun of the foreign guy.
印度人口可是比美国人口多四倍
For your information, there are four times as many
所以我们念的才是大众标准
Indians as there are Americans, so the way we say it is right.
-所以怎么念  -笑虎子[小胡子]
- Say what? - Moo-stache.
-笑虎子  -他念成笑虎子
- Moo-stache! - He said "Moo-stache"
你们两个太幼稚了
Guys, you're being childish.
她说得没错  你们都是大人了
Yeah, she's right. You're grown men,
所谓大人就是指
the kind who are perfectly capable
能留出笑虎子的人
of growing your own moo-staches.
你是讲笑话  不是无意中被笑  干得好
Hey, you were funny on purpose, good job.
抱歉迟到了  我去试镜耽搁了
Hi. Sorry I'm late-- I was at an audition.
-我也很遗憾  -下次会选上的
- Oh, I'm sorry. - You'll get 'em next time.
你们能不要直接认为我失败了
How about instead of assuming I failed,
-而是问我结果如何吗  -抱歉
- you ask me how it went? - Sorry.
-那结果如何  -问屁啊
- How did it go? - Just shut up.
来  坐你的位子吧
Here, you can have your seat.
不用不用  你坐吧  我坐地上无所谓的
No, no, no, stay there. I'm fine on the floor.
你们有想过这里搞张餐桌吗
Have you guys ever thought about getting a dining room table?
其实那边有位置放张餐桌呢
Yeah. You actually do have room for one up there.
行啊  我坐地板上几年了也无人心疼
Oh, sure, I sit on the floor for years, no one cares.
漂亮的白人妞才坐个十秒
The pretty white girl's there ten seconds,
大家就要杀到宜家买餐桌了
and suddenly we're all running to IKEA.
大家哪也不杀去
No one is running anywhere.
我们没有要买新餐桌
We're not getting a dining room table.
我知道你不喜欢改变
I know you don't like change,
但其实这主意不错啊
but it's not a terrible idea.
你们那块空间平常也只是闲置
Yeah, you guys never use that space up there.
何不搞张餐桌呢
Why not get a table?
你想要听长答案还是短答案
Do you want the long answer or the short answer?
为啥我们平常都没这福利呢
Hey, how come we never get that option?
混沌理论认为  即使在一个确定系统中
Chaos theory suggests that even in a deterministic system,
如果描述该系统变化的方程式为非线性的
if the equations describing its behavior are nonlinear,
那么初始条件最微小的改变
a tiny change in the initial conditions
也可能引起灾难性的无法预计的后果
can lead to a cataclysmic and unpredictable result.
翻译一下
Translation?
咿呀  人家不要新桌桌
Waah. I don't want a table!
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
生活大爆炸
第七季  第十六集
我要跟佩妮去逛街买新餐桌
Hey, Penny and I are gonna go shop for a dining room table.
你要一起来吗
You want to come with us?
我当然愿意
You know, I'd love to,
可是我现在抽不开身
but, um, I'm too busy
正忙着再爱Win98一遍呢
falling back in love with Windows 98.
你不是吧  你都几年没用过这桌子了
Seriously? You haven't used this desk in years.
我刚想要把它弄走  你就跑回来鼓捣东西
The second I want to get rid of it, you're up here working?
我现在没空跟你聊
I can't talk right now--
我还得安装几千个更新包呢
I have several thousand updates to install.
你真要在这赖着一整天吗
Are you really gonna sit here all day?
把我想成是《银河系漫游指南》中的亚瑟·丹特
Think of me as Arthur Dent in Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy,
躺在家的前面阻止房子被推倒
lying in front of the bulldozers to protect his home.
那你记得  渥罡人最后还是把地球全炸了吗
If you'll recall, the Vogon fleet blew up the Earth anyway.
这就是本科幻小说  莱纳德
It's a made-up story, Leonard--
我不懂你聊这个是要干嘛
I don't even know why you're talking about it.
我要把这些东西都放储藏室去
I'm putting all this stuff in storage.
全都是没用的东西
We don't need any of it.
你  你怎么能这么说
You... How can you say that?
哪件是生活中不必要的你指给我看看
You show me one thing in here we can live without.
稍等
Oh, hang on.
去你的收件箱看吧
Check your in-box.
别走  这么做真值得吗
Wait. Is this really worth it?
我们同住了这么多年
We've lived together for years
从来没有过争执
with nary an argument. Huh?
但现在就为了张桌子
But we start talking about a table,
我们却突然开始掐架了
and suddenly we're at each other's throats.
"从来没有过争执"吗
"Nary an argument"?
"从来"吗
"Nary"?!
"从来"就是指连一次都没有
Well, that means "not one," or "not any""
你与其买桌子  还是买本辞典吧
Maybe instead of a table, you should buy a dictionary.
架我是不知道掐赢了没
Well, I don't know if I won that,
但至少膈应到他了
but at least he's upset.
你看
Check it out.
电视遥控魔杖
Magic wand TV remote!
这可以遥控各种东西呢
Yeah, I can control all sorts of stuff.
伯纳黛特觉得这酷吗
Did Bernadette think it was cool?
我指着她脸说"静音"的时候肯定不觉得
Not when I said "mute" and pointed it at her face.
让我试试
Oh, uh, let me try.
转转节目转
Channelis changeroni!
这是我第二爱的棕色魔"棒"了吧
This might be my second favorite brown magic wand.
也是我最后一次再玩这东西了
Well, that's the last time I play with that.
我得去接一下
I have to take this.
您好
Hello?
关
Off.
再开
And on.
转到奥普拉女性台
And the Oprah Network.
这比当个麻瓜[凡人]看电视帅太多了
This is so much better than watching TV like a muggle.
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
我们再保持联系
We'll be in touch.
你听了一定不敢相信
You're not gonna believe this.
怎么了
What's going on?
等等
Oh. Wait.
开
On!
再关
And off!
怎么样了
What's going on?
刚才是太空总署
That was NASA.
他们想我回去太空站出任务
They want me to go back up to the space station.
那你怎么回答
Wow. What did you tell them?
我回答那是我的荣幸
I told them I'd be honored.
第二回上太空  我会想你的
A second trip to space-- I'll miss you.
我也会想念你
And I'm gonna miss you, too.
我想告诉你  我很乐意
I just want you to know, I'm happy
-在你不在的期间替你照看伯纳黛特  -谢谢
- to look in on Bernadette while you're gone. - Thank you.
如果你有什么三长两短
And if anything were to happen to you,
我和她的第一个儿子会取名霍华德
we will name our firstborn son Howard.
我就开玩笑啦
I'm just kidding.
他会取我爷爷的名字  叫迪利卜
We'll name him Dalib, after my grandfather.
这张看起来不错
Ooh, this one looks nice.
谢尔顿不喜欢回收木材质的
No. Sheldon doesn't like reclaimed wood.
为什么
Why not?
他怕原来的主人会回来找他
He's afraid the original owners will come back.
谢尔顿又不在这里
Yeah. Well, Sheldon's not here.
但他在这里
Well, he is here.
除非你愿意拿
So unless you want to dig him out
骨锯和挖球器来帮我挖出来
with a bone saw and a melon baller,
否则我也无能为力
there's nothing I can do about it.
宝贝  这张桌子出钱的人是你
All right, sweetie, you're paying for this table,
公寓也是你们共有的
and it's your apartment, too.
-我知道  但是...  -不许说但是
- I know, but... - No buts.
你不能再让他对你颐指气使了
You got to stop letting him boss you around.
有道理  每次都是他决定看什么电视节目
You're right. I mean, h-he decides what TV shows we watch,
吃什么东西  我最喜欢哪个霍比特人
what food we eat, who my favorite hobbit is--
我最喜欢弗罗多  但是他说不能重复
I wanted Frodo, but we can't both have Frodo,
你猜谁被逼去喜欢小肥仔山姆·詹吉了
so guess who's stuck with Samwise Gamgee.
你看  活生生的例子  你是大人了
See? Right there. You're a grown man,
你有权选择自己最爱的霍比特人是哪个
you should be able to pick whichever hobbit you want.
希望你没那么宅  但一次解决一问题吧
Wish you wouldn't, but one problem at a time.
你的话很有道理
Y-You make a lot of sense.
我喜欢这张桌子  我要买了
I like this table, and I'm getting it.
真的吗  这张啊
Really? This one?
那张呢
That one?
爷他妈要的就是这张了
Damn right I like that one.
有好消息宣布
Good news.
这房间里的某人能够"骑火箭升空"哦
Someone in this room gets to take a ride on a rocket.
好吧  我能至少先洗个澡吗
Fine. Can I at least shower first?
不是指那方面
No, not that.
但你答应了要骑我"火箭"也不许反悔
Although you already agreed to it, so no take-backs.
那你本来是指什么
What are you talking about?
先坐下
Sit down.
太空总署打来了
NASA called.
我之前给太空站
The telescope mount I installed
装的望远镜架坏了
on the space station got damaged,
他们现在想让我回去修好它
and they want me to go back up and fix it.
那你怎么回答
Well, what did you say?
你觉得呢  我当然十分乐意啊
What do you think I...? I said yes!
你干嘛看起来一脸惊讶
Why do you look surprised?
因为上次之后
Well, it's just, after last time,
我以为你不会再想重回太空
I didn't think you'd ever want to go back.
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding?
-上太空可是我这辈子最棒的体验  -是吗
- It was the greatest experience of my life. - Really?
我怎么记得有人在无穷无尽地抱怨
'Cause I kind of remember a lot of complaining
哭爹喊娘盼着早日结束
and wishing for it to be over.
我觉得你说的是不是我
I think you have me confused with
而是等下洗完澡之后的你吧
what's gonna happen when you get out of that shower.
桌子摆好了  你觉得怎么样
Hey, all set. What do you think?
人人都有座  不用挤在一起
There's plenty of room for everybody,
吃饭时还能欣赏窗外景色
a view out the window.
我在沙发上的专座也能欣赏窗外景色
My spot on the couch has a great view of a window.
有时我还能看见太空大战呢
Sometimes I can see space battles through it.
那扇窗就叫电视
It's called a TV.
试试嘛  谢尔顿  没准你会喜欢呢
Give it a chance, Sheldon; you might actually like it.
你说得很对
You're absolutely right.
不喜欢
Nope.
他也算有"好好"试过一回了
Well, you can't say he didn't give it a fair shot.
那我们什么时候可以扔掉它
So, when can we get rid of it?
才不扔呢
We're not.
《室友协议》上是怎么规定的
What about the roommate agreement?
上面明确指出
It specifically states
凡是家具发生改动
that any changes in furnishing
都必须得经过家具委员会的同意
have to be approved by the Furnishing Committee.
而他们是隔年才开一次会
Which only sits on alternate years.
对了  顺便说一句
Yeah, and by the way,
委员会就坐[开会]这个位置
it sits over there.
-拜托  这规定太扯了吧  -她说得对
- Come on, that is ridiculous. - She's right--
这么重要的委员会应该经常开会才对
a committee that important should meet more often.
我不是那个意思
That's not what I'm saying.
你是指让我勇敢反抗
This is the thing about me standing up to him
-不要让他操控我的人生吗  -对
- and not letting him run my life? - Yes.
我就那意思
That.
好吧  我知道问题在哪儿了
Okay. I think we've found the problem here.
问题根本不在餐桌
It's not the table at all.
-而是在你  -我吗
- It's you. - Me?
平时他老怪我  这次你就牺牲下吧
Well, it's always me-- take one for the team.
我花了多年时间把这块烂泥
I have spent years turning this lump of clay
按照我的意愿打造成我能接受的室友
into an acceptable conduit for my will,
然后你出现  用你新奇的想法
and then you came along and reshaped him,
和华丽丽的生殖器改造了他
with your newfangled ideas and your fancy genitals.
你就让他这么跟我说话吗
Are you gonna let him talk to me like this?
"华丽丽"这个词听上去像是夸你啊
"Fancy" sounds like a compliment.
好吧  我没有要试着改变莱纳德
Okay, I have not tried to change Leonard.
只是恋爱中的人都会这样
That's just what happens in relationships.
瞧瞧你被艾米改变了多少
Look how much Amy's changed you.
-才没有呢  -拜托
- That's not true. - Oh, please.
我刚认识你时  你根本无法
When I first met you, you were incapable
跟任何人产生身体接触
of touching another human being.
现在你会跟人拉手  你会跟人约会
Now you're holding hands, you're going on dates,
你甚至在火车上跟她接吻
you even made out with her on a train.
她居然告诉你了
She told you?!
她当然告诉我了  这是这辈子
Of course she told me-- it's the most interesting thing
发生在她身上最有趣的事情
that's ever happened to her in her entire life!
你是当事人才没意识到
You're too close to it,
但艾米的确对你影响很大
but Amy has had a huge impact on you.
你说得对
You're right.
我一直没意识到  我默默让那女人
Without realizing it, I've allowed that woman
改变了我的个性
to alter my personality.
谢尔顿  你没有个性
Mm, Sheldon, you didn't have a personality;
你只是有几个爱看的节目而已
you just had some shows you liked.
不
No.
不  我是改变了
No, I've changed.
就像一只被放进一锅水的青蛙
Like the frog who's put in a pot of water
水是被慢慢加热的
that's heated so gradually
所以青蛙根本意识不到自己会被煮死
he doesn't realize he's boiling to death.
或者你是一只被公主吻了的青蛙
Or you're the frog who's been kissed by a princess
最终会变成王子
and turned into a prince.
又或者你是一只惹人烦的高个青蛙
Or you're just a tall, annoying frog.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
我要去跟我女朋友分手
I have to break up with my girlfriend.
-谢尔顿  等等  -不
- Oh, Sheldon, wait. - No.
是你们让我看清了真相
You've opened my eyes to the truth.
艾米把我变成了一个感情更丰富
Amy has made me a more affectionate,
思想更开明的人
open-minded person.
改变到此结束
And that stops now.
-我们应该打给她  -是啊
- Well, we should call her. - Yeah, mm-hmm.
艾米  我是佩妮
Amy, it's Penny. Hey.
先给你提个醒
Just a little heads-up.
莱纳德买了一张餐桌
Leonard bought a dining room table.
是的  谢尔顿要跟你分手
Yeah. Sheldon's breaking up with you.
艾米  艾米
Amy? Amy?
艾米
Amy?
我就直截了当地说吧
I'll get right to the point.
我觉得我们应该结束这段感情  所以
I think we need to end this relationship-- so...
麻烦你用手在这上面签名  对了
just sign this with your finger, and, uh,
眼泪不要掉到我的iPad上
please don't cry on my iPad--
我的机子没保修服务
I didn't get AppleCare.
我不意外你会想结束我们这段感情
I'm not surprised you want to end the relationship.
让我意外的是  你居然没买保修
I'm a little surprised you didn't get AppleCare.
总之好好享受你的人生  我要在哪里签名
Anyway, enjoy your life. Where do I sign?
最下面  不得不说
At the bottom. I must say,
你没有对此大哭大闹  我感到很欣慰
I'm relieved you're not making more of a scene out of this.
我已经看开了
Oh, I've already moved on.
再说了  这次分手又不是我的错
Besides, this breakup has nothing to do with me.
-是吗  -当然
- Wh... It doesn't? - Of course not.
这只是莱纳德故意挑拨我们感情
This is just Leonard trying to take the focus off
想把焦点从那张让人讨厌的餐桌转移走
that dreadful table by sowing discord in our relationship.
他总是这样把你玩弄于股掌之中
He's manipulating you like he always does.
慢着慢着  先别签
Wait-wait, now, hang on.
你觉得他在操控我思想吗
You think he manipulates me?
向来如此
All the time.
他肯定知道
And he knew that,
我作为你的女朋友  我不会袖手旁观
as your girlfriend, I wasn't gonna stand by
让他把那张桌子搬进你的公寓
and let him bring a table into your apartment.
一张破餐桌  有没有搞错啊
I mean, a table? Come on!
那餐桌难看死了
It is hideous.
谢天谢地  我不用看见它
Well, thankfully, I won't have to see it,
因为我再也不是你的女朋友了
'cause I won't be your girlfriend anymore.
艾米·菲拉·福勒
Amy Farrah Fowler.
好的  我愿意填写用户问卷
Why, yes, I would like to take a survey.
慢着
Wait.
之前你真的会站在我这边
You were really gonna stand by me
跟我一起反对那张餐桌进驻吗
against the dining room table?
当然啦
Of course I was.
好吧  等等
Yeah, wait.
我怎么知道你现在不是在试图摆布我呢
How do I know that you're not manipulating me right now?
如果我在摆布你
I think if I were manipulating you,
你这么聪明肯定能看出来
you'd be smart enough to see it.
我怎么知道你这么说
How do I know you're not saying that
不是你摆布我的其中一步
as part of the manipulation?
我觉得你这么聪明  也一定能看出来
I think you'd be smart enough to see that, too.
好吧
Okay.
抱歉让你难过了  我只是想确认一下
I'm sorry I gave you such a hard time-- I just had to be sure.
太空总署让霍华德重返太空
It's pretty exciting that NASA
真是超级让人兴奋呀
wants to send Howard back up.
是啊  好兴奋啊
Yeah, exciting.
-我能问你个问题吗  -当然
- Can I ask you something? - Course.
他明明讨厌在太空的整个过程
He hated that entire experience.
我不支持他重返太空
Does it make me an awful wife
是不是就成了糟糕的妻子啊
if I don't think he should do it again?
完全不会
Not at all.
他只是忘了他在太空的
He's forgotten how miserable he was
整个过程有多悲催
the entire time he was up there.
就像我思念印度的那些时刻
It's like me in those moments when I miss India.
-那你会跟他谈吗  -为什么是我
- So you'll talk to him? - Why me?
我是他妻子  我不想泼他冷水
Well, I'm his wife; I don't want to ruin it for him.
我们之间就是这样啊
That's the dynamic--
我是开心果  你是扫兴鬼
I'm the fun one, you're the buzzkill.
我从什么时候起是扫兴鬼了
Since when am I the buzzkill?
你觉得这个酷吗
Do you think this is cool?
不  我觉得这个很傻
No, I think it's stupid.
你说得对  这个太酷了
You're right, it's great.
你们好啊
Hello.
你们没有分手啊
You guys didn't break up.
没有  抱歉让你失望了
No. Sorry to disappoint you,
但艾米指出来
but Amy pointed out that
你只是想操控我
you were only trying to manipulate me.
这一点是你自己想明白的
Which you also figured out by yourself.
这一点是我自己想明白的
Which I also figured out by myself.
我很开心你们依然在一起
Well, I'm glad you're still together.
好啦  你别再试图
Yeah, okay, you can stop trying
把矛盾点扯到我们的感情上
to make this about our relationship.
我们感情情比金坚
Which is stronger than ever.
这次都怪你  试图改变我的生活环境
This is about you trying to change my environment,
而本来的环境就很完美
which was perfect the way it was.
但这个完美也是通过改变而来的
But it got the way it was through change.
这个你喜欢的专座
The-the spot that you love to sit in,
你不让别人坐的专座
that no one else can sit in,
之所以存在的唯一原因是
only exists because--
我不顾你的反对买了这个沙发
despite your objections-- I bought this couch.
所以得谢谢我
Me.
所以请你解释下  为什么那个改变不好
So explain why that change was bad
而这个改变是好的
and this change was good.
你不必向他解释你的想法
You don't need to explain yourself to him.
我不必向你解释我的想法
I don't need to explain myself to you!
你已经受够了他的废话  准备和我同居
You're sick of his nonsense and ready to move in with me.
破餐桌爱留就留  我们不差那点空间
Keep the table! We don't use that space!
娘的  我太得意忘形了
Damn it, I got cocky.
妮妮  我回来了  大家好
Hey, Bernie. I'm home... Hello.
你好  亲爱的
Hi, honey.
出什么事了
What's going on?
或许你该先坐下
Maybe you should have a seat.
好吧
Um... okay.
我知道我妈没过世  否则就有气球装饰了
I know my mom's not dead; there'd be balloons.
首先
First off,
你要知道我们都爱你珍惜你
know that we all love you and cherish you.
-我算不上...  -老爸
- Well, I wouldn't... - Daddy.
你很棒
You're great.
-我能说几句吗  -当然
- Can I say something? - Oh, of course.
你好  果麦圈客
Hey, Fruit Loops.
马西米诺  你怎么也在
Massimino? Why are you here?
我听说你在考虑
Well, I heard you were thinking about
重返太空站的事
going back up to the space station,
作为和你在上面共事过的战友...
and as someone who's been there with you...
你知道宇航员必须具备"正确的质素"吧
well, you know how astronauts need to have the "right stuff"?
当然知道
Sure.
你所具备的质素都是错的
The stuff you have is wrong.
你觉得我在上面的工作并不优秀吗
You don't think I did a good job up there?
你做得还行
You did a fine job.
只是  整个过程你一直怕得半死  悲惨不堪
It's just, you were scared and miserable the whole time.
我想大家想说的是
I think what we're all trying to say is,
你似乎不记得
you don't seem to be remembering
这段太空之旅带给了你多大的创伤
how traumatic the experience was for you.
好比说女人经常会忘记分娩的痛苦
L-Like how women often forget the pain of childbirth.
好比女人  这比喻不错
Like a woman. Great analogy.
好吧  也许我当时是有些害怕
Fine, maybe I was a little scared.
你尿在了宇航服里
You peed in your space suit.
本来就是该尿在里面啊
You're supposed to do that.
不是在试穿的时候
Not during the fitting.
孩子  需要我提醒你上次你升空前
Son, do I need to remind you what you asked me to do
你求我做什么吗
before you went up last time?
慢着  我那只是开玩笑
Hang on. That was just me joking around.
你要我冲你的脚开枪
You wanted me to shoot you in the foot.
这怎么可能不是玩笑啦
Come on, how is that not a joke?
"你得帮我脱身  冲我的脚开枪"
"You got to get me out of this. Shoot me in the foot."
别忘了其他宇航员欺负你的事
Don't forget all the other astronauts picking on you.
还有你在失重环境下吐了
And how you threw up in zero gravity,
呕吐物又飘回到你嘴里
and it floated back in your mouth.
然后你又吐了
And you threw up again.
这过程周而复始
And so on and so on.
那蛮搞笑的
That was funny.
我在上面的表现是比不上约翰·格伦[著名宇航员]
Okay, so I wasn't exactly John Glenn up there,
但我改变了  我现在不同了
but I've changed; I'm a different man now.
你们觉得我不能胜任
Yeah, and I'm a little insulted
让我有种被羞辱的感觉
that you guys don't think I can handle it.
你知道你还得再次通过生存训练吧
You know you're gonna have to go through survival training again.
是吗
Really?
你得帮我脱身
You've got to get me out of this!
你想要我怎么做  你太健康了
What do you want me to do? You're perfectly healthy.
再量下我的血压
Check my blood pressure again!
我可以让血压升高  稍等
I can get it higher; just give me a second.
-喂  -妈  你好吗
- Hello? - Hi, Ma. How are you?
老娘还没死呢
How I am is not dead!
但你不会知道
But you wouldn't know that,
因为你根本不爱我  电话都懒得打
because you don't love me enough to pick up the phone!
你得知道  我有可能在浴缸滑倒摔死
For all you know, I could have slipped in the tub and drowned!
快量快量
Go, go, go!
你艾达阿姨就是这么死的
That's what happened to your Aunt Ida!
霍华德  真遗憾你的血压这么高
Howard, I'm so sorry your blood pressure was off the charts.
我也是  医生倒是愿意
Oh, me, too. I mean, the doctor was willing
为我捏造健康报告  但是
to fudge the results, but...
那太他娘不诚实了
it just seemed so darned dishonest.
但离任务开始不是至少还有一年吗
But the mission wouldn't be for at least a year.
你的血压不是还有足够时间恢复到...
Isn't that enough time to get your blood pressure under...
我知道我血压太高  别再提这事了
Look, my blood pressure's too high, okay? Drop it.
我姨妈改变了饮食习惯
You know, my aunt changed her diet,
-几个月后  她...  -上了太空吗
- and in a few months, she... - Went to space?
我想不可能吧  把酱油递给我
I don't think so. Now, pass the soy sauce.
不要绿色那瓶  要红色的
Hey, not the green one; the red one.
谢尔顿  艾米  过来和我们一起吃好吗
Sheldon, Amy, will you please come join us?
是啊  这里很欢乐
Yeah, it's fun up here.
那你为什么要毁了欢乐时光呢
So why are you trying to ruin it?
好意心领了  我们很好
No, thanks. We're fine.
如果你们想在餐桌上吃饭
I mean, if you people want to eat at the table,
你们就在那里吃吧
then that's what you should do.
我喜欢在这里吃饭
I like eating down here
因为我们以前一直是这样
because this is how we've always done things.
如果过去的岁月逝去了  那就随风去吧
But if those days are gone, they're gone.
只是  让我很伤心
It just... makes me sad.
现在我也伤心了
Now I feel bad.
别把他当人看  他有双无辜大眼
Oh, don't anthropomorphize him; he's got big eyes,
但他的情感和我们人类不同
but his feelings are not like ours.
不  我们分成两组坐看起来好傻
No, it just seems silly for us to sit in two groups.
如果你把那组的领导人
Well, it's not silly if you think of that group
想成是巨型魔婴  就不会觉得傻了
as being led by a big, evil baby.
看艾米坐在那里的样子
Look at Amy down there.
我们应该过去吗
Should we go?
好吧  我们过去
Yeah, let's go.
但是  佩妮  这原本是你的主意
But... Penny, this was your idea.
你说我应该奋起和他抗争
You said that I should stand up to him.
算了吧  莱纳德
Forget it, Leonard.
抗战结束
It's over.
好吧
Fine.
拉杰什
Rajesh?
去死吧  我在地板上坐了七年
Screw that! I sat on the floor for seven years.
人家要坐在这里
I'm staying right here!
来吧  拉杰  有你感觉才完整
Come on, Raj, it's not the same without you.
好吧
Fine.
但不许再嘲笑我说的"花"[话]
But no more making fun of how I say tings.
你说的"花"是指"笑虎子"吗
You mean "tings" like "moo-stache"?
大家齐聚一堂感觉真好
Well, isn't this nice.
偶尔魔婴也有赢的时候嘛
Sometimes the baby wins.